<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conscientious Code</title>
    <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Conscientious Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 15:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://patrickcole.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using JSON With Localstorage</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/using-json-with-localstorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/using-json-with-localstorage/</guid>
      <description>Remember that JSON has to be formatted before it can be saved and properly parsed when retrieved. These gotchas can hurt if you are working with JavaScript objects and are expecting them to be native objects from the start.
When saving JSON data to storage, make sure that you are calling the JSON.stringify() method on your object either before or during the localStorage.setItem(&#39;key&#39;, value) call. What this ensures is that the value will be a properly formatted JSON string and will retain its relationship data and values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Careful With Env Files</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/be-careful-with-env-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:59:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/be-careful-with-env-files/</guid>
      <description>Oh they are soo nice to work with aren&amp;rsquo;t they? Until you realize that you accidentally uploaded one to your public repository. That&amp;rsquo;s what I accidentally did today. Fortunately, I caught it early on so that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any issues with my database that I&amp;rsquo;m using.
I have learned from this that I really need to think ahead with dealing with environment variables. Simply placing them in as an afterthought or during prototyping is not a great idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>react-youtube</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/dependencies/react-youtube/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 16:06:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/dependencies/react-youtube/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted to post a quick article on this new dependency I found recently. The react-youtube module is very useful for getting an embedded YouTube video inside your applications. I found the installation and configuration of the module to be very easy.
It&amp;rsquo;s also important to note that this module will work with the YouTube IFrame Player API and has links to the documentation for configuration. I have implemented a copy of this module inside my latest project react-OST where I am using the player for embedding soundtrack videos that have been uploaded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/network/http2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 09:52:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/network/http2/</guid>
      <description>Designed to make webpages and applications load resources much faster and reducing the number of connections.
Better performance in the transport layer of the browser&amp;rsquo;s stack of webpage processing.
Enables multiplexing requests and responses for quicker concurrent transfer of data.
Adds support for prioritization of requests and server push commands.
Additional features such as:
 New flow control Error handling Mechanisms for upgrading  HTTP/2 is built on-top of the existing standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preload</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/performance/preload/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/performance/preload/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Pages Resources  Pages Preloading a page tells the browser that the user is definitely going to visit a page and the browser should get that page ready to load immediately.
For example, an application has an intro screen to describe what the application is about. Once users accept entry into the application, the logical next page they would visit would be the home or main page. Ideally, users would want that page to load as quickly as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Path</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/performance/critical-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:05:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/performance/critical-path/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Critical Path&amp;rdquo; defines the process of the browser downloading, parsing and rendering a webpage. This is broken up into the following process:
 Network download HTML DOM parse CSSOM parse Layout Paint / Render JavaScript onload  There are many bottlenecks that can occur during these steps and limiting issues in each one is paramount to delivering a quick and performant webpage.
Network Download Note: Downloading additional assets can add time to first paint or interactive mode</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prefetching</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/performance/prefetching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 13:22:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/topics/performance/prefetching/</guid>
      <description>Pre-fetching gives the browser the ability to know what resources will need to be downloaded right away or in the future.
Contents  DNS prefetching Resources  DNS prefetching Useful if assets are going to be downloaded from an external URL (other than hosted domain). For example, if fonts are going to be loaded from CDN, the DNS prefetching hint can tell the browser to start a connection to that location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentions</title>
      <link>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 12:40:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patrickcole.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is just the start of my findings, notes and examples. I hope that I can use this platform to show my progression of learning things. It will also be helpful for me as I try to pull together all those topics that make up the web. I will do my best to try to keep things updated, but as we know, the web moves very quickly. Also, it is my intention to keep topics organized so that when I need to locate something for research, reference or discussion, I will have it at the ready.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>